Guide to the Nils John Nilsson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Publications, Series 8
  - Correspondence April 1989 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence April 1989 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence May 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence June 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence July 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence August 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence September 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, originally filed after Correspondence September 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Life article, "Shaky" November 1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Dartmouth (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fellows Symposium AAAI (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 2006 & 2007 Conference Agendas (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Switzerland (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Complete Intelligence Workshop February 2009 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - AI: A New Synthesis, (errata to be added) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Comments/Reviews G&N (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Reviews: New Synthesis (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Principles of AI – Processed Comments on New Book Draft (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Reviews: Learning Machine (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Reviews: Problem Solving Methods in AI (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Linguistic Institute 1987 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - American Library Association June 1987 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Humanities, Animals, and Machines April 1987 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Parlor Talk March 1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - RADC May 13, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Hewlett-Packard March 19, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - AF Talk Agenda 1986 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - WPMFB Talk April 22, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - ICA Presentation 1986 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Fantasy, Toronto, November 1985 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - AI Retreat August 2, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Columbia Talk April 29, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Bank of America Talk 1985 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - A Short Rebuttal to Searle, November 6, 1984 – OTA Workshop (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - WDC November 1984 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Illinois Talk Fall 1984 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - DARPA/Schwartz Presentation October 21, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Santa Cruz Planning Workshop October 21-23, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Publications (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Publications 1959-1990 (1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Publications 1959-1990 (2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Publications 1959-1990 (3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Photos IJCAI 1973 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Problem Solving Methods in AI Galleys (1 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Problem Solving Methods in AI Galleys (2 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Problem Solving Methods in AI Galleys (3 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Problem Solving Methods in AI Galleys (4 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Problem Solving Methods in AI Galleys (5 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript for Learning Machines (1 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript for Learning Machines (2 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript for Learning Machines (3 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript for Learning Machines (4 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript for Learning Machines (5 of 5) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Alfred E. Brain with attached article (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Audiovisual materials, Series 9
  - Shakey the Robot [color positive sound print], with invoice from W. A. Palmer Films, 1982 and 1986; 8.01; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); film reel (16mm) (Box 8)
  - "Shakey: Experimentation in Robot Planning and Learning" film transfer, 9-22-83; 8.02; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic); videotape (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - SRITAPE ASCII. Possibly contains files for BIBLIO.HP, chapters 1-9, PREFACE.HP, PROL.HP, PROS.HP, 8.03; 1 computer tape(s); computer tape (Box 8)
  - Artificial Intelligence Controversy Robots Tape 1, 8/20/73; 8.04; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic); videotape (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Artificial Intelligence Controversy Robots Tape 2, 8/20/73; 8.05; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic); videotape (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Artificial Intelligence Controversy Robots, 8/20/73; 8.06; 1 videotape(s) (VHS); videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
  - Giving Machines Some Thought (documentary on AI) [28:20], 1986; 8.07; 1 videotape(s) (VHS); videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
  - Giving Machines Some Thought (documentary on AI) [124:00], 1986; 8.08; videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
  - Genetic Programming III Video Sampler. Human-Competitive Machine Intelligence, April 1999; 8.09; 1 videotape(s) (VHS); videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
  - "Shakey: Experimentation in Robot Planning and Learning", 8.10; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Edward A. Feigenbaum Festschrift, Tape 1 of 3, March 25, 2006; 8.11; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Edward A. Feigenbaum Festschrift, Tape 2 of 3, March 25, 2006; 8.12; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Edward A. Feigenbaum Festschrift, Tape 3 of 3, March 25, 2006; 8.13; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Computer History Museum. Oral History of Ed Feigenbaum, Session 1, May 20, 2007; 8.14; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Computer History Museum. Oral History of Ed Feigenbaum, Session 2, [as labeled], May 2, 2007; 8.15; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Computer History Museum. Oral History of John Backus, September 5, 2006; 8.16; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD); optical disc (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Celebrating AAAI's Twenty-Fifth Anniversary: 20th National Conference on Artificial Intelligence, July 2005; 8.17; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - AAAI and IAAI proceedings, 2006; 8.18; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - 17th International Joint Conference on AI, Seattle, 2001 Aug 4-10; 8.19; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - 18th International Joint Conference on AI, Mexico, 2003; 8.20; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - International conference on Robotics and Automation proceedings, April 2000; 8.21; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - AAAI Technical Papers: National Conferences on AI 1998-99, Knowledge Discover & Data Mining Conferences, 1995-1998, 1995-99; 8.22-8.23; 2 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - Performance Metrics for Intelligent Systems Workshop, Proceedings of PerMIS '06 Workshop, 2006; 8.24; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-ROM); optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - Robotic Autonomy, Carnegie Mellon Institute [course curriculum and administrative material], Summer 2002; 8.25; optical disc (CD) (Box 8)
  - AI Debate – UC Berkeley; Weizenbaum, Coles, Dreyfus, circa 1973; 8.26; 1 audiocassette(s); audiocassette (Box 8)
- Correspondence, Series 10
  - Dec. 1958-Dec. 1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1963 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1964 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1964 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1966 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1966 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1967 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1967 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1968 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1968 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1969 (1 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1969 (2 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1969 (3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 1970 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 1970 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - 1973 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - 1974 (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1974 (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1975 (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1975 (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1976 (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1976 (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1976 (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1978 (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1978 (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 1980 (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 1980 (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 1980 (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - 1980 (More) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - 1981 (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - 1981 (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - 1981 (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - 1981 (Possible duplicates?) (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - 1981 (Possible duplicates?) (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - January-March 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - April-July 1982 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - April-July 1982 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - April-December 1982 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - April-December 1982 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1983 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1983 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1983, second file (1 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1983, second file (2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1983, second file (3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1983, third file (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1983, third file (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - July-November 1984 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - July-November 1984 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - December 1983-March 1984 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - 1984 (1 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - 1984 (2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - 1984 (3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - January-November 1985 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - April-December 1986 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - 1987 Jan (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - 1987 Feb (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1987 Mar (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1987 Apr (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1987 May (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1987 Jun (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1987 Jul (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1987 Aug (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1987 Sep (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1987 Oct (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 1987 Nov (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1987 Dec (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1988 Jan (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 1988 Feb (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 1988 Mar (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - 1988 Apr (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - 1988 May (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - 1988 Jun (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1988 Jul (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1988 Aug (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1988 Sep (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1988 Oct (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1988 Nov (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1988 Dec (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1989 Jan (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1989 Feb (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1989 Mar (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1989 Oct (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1989 Nov (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 1989 Dec (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 1990 Jan (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 1990 Feb (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - 1990 Mar (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 1990 Apr (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - 1990 May (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - 1990 Jun (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - 1990 Jul (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - 1990 Aug (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - 1990 Sep (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - 1990 Nov (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - 1990 Dec (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - 1991 Jan (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - 1991 Feb (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - 1991 Mar (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - 1991 Apr (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - 1991 May (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - 1991 Jun (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - 1991 Jul (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - 1991 Aug (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - 1991 Sep (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - 1991 Oct (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - 1991 Nov (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - 1992 Jan (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1992 Feb (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1992 Mar (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1992 Apr (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1992 May (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1992 Jun (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1992 Jul (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1992 Aug (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1992 Sep (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1992 Oct (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 1992 Nov (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1992 Dec (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1992 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 1993 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 1994 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1995 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1996 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - 1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - 1998 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 1999 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - 2000- (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous, Series 11
  - Fein, Louis, "Study and Evaluation of the Status of University Programs in the United States in Computers, Data-Processing and Related Fields Including Recommendations to Stanford University on Their Potential Role in These Fields," October 1957 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Mapping Great Debates: Can Computers Think? An Issue Map Publication 1998 [Handbook and 7 large diagrams] (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "A Word in Edgewise," newsletter on AI by Dick Fredericksen, #5-8, January – June 1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of Machine Intelligence and Perception, University of Edinburgh: list of staff publications 1966-70 and A Seven Year Project to Develop an Intelligent Problem-Solving System, Oct. 1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Fein, Louis, The Artificial Intelligentsia, WESCON 63 paper, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Assorted memos (SRI, DARPA, Xerox PARC, SU Dept. of CS) 1967-84 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Winston, Patrick H. Proposal to the Advanced Research Projects Agency May 1976. MIT A.I. Memo 366 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - McCarthy, John. Project Technical Report. Stanford Artificial Intelligence Project Memo AI-87. June 1969 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Neural Network Synthesis Using Cellular Encoding and the Genetic Algorithm. Thesis by Frederic Gruau, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Une Application de l'Intelligence Artificielle a la Conception Assistee par Ordinateur. Thesis by Jean-Claude Latombe, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning: A Hybrid Approach. Thesis by Malcolm Ross Kinsella Ryan, Univ. of New South Wales, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The Use of a Lattice in Knowledge Processing. Thesis by Gernhard Deon Oosthuizen, University of Strathclyde, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Intelligence by Design: Principles of Modularity and Coordination for Engineering Complex Adaptive Agents. Thesis by Joanna Joy Bryson, MIT, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 4)